[MUSIC]
[음악]
In this module, Emily showed us how to build product recommenders and
이 모듈에서 에밀리가 상품 추천기 구축과
algorithms associated with recommender systems.
연관 알고리즘을 설명했습니다
Now, we're gonna build a notebook to recommend songs
이제 듣고 싶은만한 노래를 추천하는
we might want to listen to.
노트북을 만들 겁니다
This is gonna be really quite cool.
아주 신나는 것이죠
Okay, so this is going to be the, we're gonna rename our notebook here.
노트북 제목을 바꿉니다
This is the Song recommender.
노래 추천기입니다
So again, I'm going to hide the header and
다시 한번 헤더와 툴바를 감춰서
hide the toolbar to show you this a little more space.
공간을 확보합니다
And as usual, we're gonna start by importing graphlab.
평소와 같이 graphlab 도입으로 시작합니다
Okay, let's start here.
시작해볼까요
And the first thing that we're gonna do is load some music data.
처음으로 음악 데이터를 읽어옵니다
So, we're gonna load music data.
음악 데이터 읽어오기
This is a really cool dataset, it's called the Million Song Dataset.
노래 백만 곡 데이터 세트라고 합니다
And we're gonna create a variable called song_data.
song_data란 변수를 생성합니다
It's gonna store it.
여기
And we're gonna have a graphlab.SFrame where
graphlab.SFrame에
we're reading it and this is some data that dropped.
song_data.gl을 읽어 저장합니다
So here we are, we're reading it and so
이렇게 읽었으면
let's start doing a little bit of data exploration.
가볍게 데이터 탐색부터 해봅시다
So let's do some exploring over
SFrame 데이터인 음악 데이터를
a friend data here, music data.
탐색해봅니다
So first thing that we're gonna do, as usual,
가장 먼저 평소대로
is take the song_data and take a look at the first few lines of this table.
song_data 표의 처음 몇 줄을 살펴봅니다
And so here's what the song data looks like.
이게 song_data의 모습입니다
A user for user ID.
표에는 사용자 ID
Listen to a song once or twice.
들은 횟수
This is the title of the song, this is the artist and
노래 제목, 가수,
this is the song itself.
노래까지 있습니다
The title is the title of the record mentioned.
제목은 노래가 아닌 음반 제목입니다
And so, as we can see, we just have
그리고 우리에게 주어진 건 각 사용자가
a table that shows us how often each person listens to different songs.
어떤 노래를 얼마나 들었는지 나타내는 표입니다
And then we're gonna use this to build a recommender
이를 통해 관심이 갈만한 노래를 찾는
that finds out other songs you might be interested in listening to.
추천기를 만듭니다
And we're gonna explore a couple different types of recommenders
에밀리와 모듈에서 같이 알아봤듯이
as Emily shared with us in the module.
여러 유형의 추천기를 탐구하게 됩니다
So as usual I'm going to, I like showing the histogram on the notebook itself.
평소와 같이 노트북에 히스토그램을 그릴 겁니다
So I'm gonna do graphlab.canvas.set_target and
set_target에
I'm gonna say a ipynb.
ipynb를 인자로 줍니다
And then after we done that I'm gonna take my song_data.
그런 다음 song_data에서
And I'm going to look at particular column, let's say the song column and
특정 열을 찾는데 노래 열이라고 하고
type.show in it, which is gonna show me
.show를 입력하면 여러 노래와 재생 빈도
a histogram of the different songs and how often they're played.
히스토그램이 같이 나옵니다
And here we are.
나왔죠
So, this is the different songs by title, and
제목별로 노래가 나오는데
you see how this song here was played 5,970 times.
이 노래는 5970번 재생됐네요
This Bjork song was played 5,281 times.
Bjork 노래는 5281번 재생됐고요
This song here, this is a Brazilian song.
이 노래는 브라질 노래인데
TVC by Catola, 3,185 times.
Catola의 TVC는 3185번입니다
And so some people really like their songs and they play them a lot.
노래를 좋아해서 여러 번 듣는 사람도 있죠
So this is the kind of data we're looking at, and
우리가 보는 데이터는 이렇고
if you take a quick look at this song data you'll see at the length.
곡 데이터의 길이를 잠깐 보면
You see we're talking about here 1.1 million songs.
110만곡이 있음을 확인할 수 있습니다
So million song user pair, so this is ratings, song ratings.
백만 곡, 사용자 짝이니 곡 평점입니다
And this is what the dataset is, a pretty large dataset.
이게 데이터 세트인데 무척 큽니다
But we're gonna do some things together on this large data set right here.
이 큰 데이터 세트를 함께 다루는 작업을 해보죠
So let's ask, let's do a little bit more exploration.
일단 데이터 탐색부터 해봅시다
So we said for each user, there's 1 million,
각 사용자에게, 평점 백만 개 또는
about a million ratings or a million number of listens.
들은 횟수가 백만 개 있습니다
Let's see how many users are involved here.
사용자가 몇 명이나 되는지 봅시다
So, I'm going to, let's say,
지금부터
oops, ##Count number of users.
##사용자 숫자 세기를 합니다
So, in doing this, I'm gonna show you another little trick which is useful
그와 동시에 데이터 세트 탐색에 유용한
as you're exploring your own dataset.
요령 하나 보여드리죠
So, I am gonna create a new array here for users.
사용자의 배열을 새로 만듭니다
And this is going to take the song data that
곡 데이터에서
we have and look at the user_id column.
사용자 id 열을 봅니다
And I'm gonna ask you apply the unique command.
unique 명령어를 적용합니다
And what the unique command does is select out of all these users,
unique 명령어는 모든 사용자 중에
just shows the unique different users that we have.
중복을 제거하고 보여줍니다
Just all the unique ones.
그러니까 순 사용자들이죠
And so, if I ask for the length of users,
사용자 길이를 구하면
you should see that we have 66,346 unique users
백만 곡이 있는 이 데이터 세트에는
in this dataset with 1 million different song.
순 사용자 66346명이 있습니다
You think about ratings, but number of times you listen to some,
나머지는 평점이라 생각하시겠지만
song activity rows.
재생 빈도 행입니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]